All right. Good evening uh everyone and
happy
Sabbath.
>> Yes. Welcome,
>> welcome, welcome, welcome.
Uh
we're just making sure that we got
everything uh set up here, guys. So,
just give us a moment, please.
Good to see all of you here
>> tonight. I know we're all around the
world. So, some of you it may be early
morning, maybe even afternoon if you're
in
>> late afternoon in Australia or other in
that part of the world, but so glad that
you are here with us and we're excited
to present tonight's topic. I am a
student with you tonight.
>> Yes.
>> So, we're going to be learning together
and I'm excited for that. Hopefully, you
can hear us well. Let us know if you can
hear us. Hopefully, we're not too The
sound is not too faint.
>> Yeah. Um
All right. Good, good, good. Okay, guys.
So, uh tonight
um we are going to be looking at
something that
uh is [clears throat]
uh absolutely significant,
excuse me,
for the time that we are living in. And
um you know, as we go through this study
tonight, it's uh I can promise you it's
going to be challenging.
Um,
it's going to be challenging for
for a lot of people.
>> So,
um, we got to do something real quick
here, guys. So, just give us a second.
Okay.
>> And we're back.
>> And we're back. And we're back. Uh,
okay, guys. So, uh, put a one in the
chat if you could hear us. If I need to
move my mic up.
>> Yeah, I think they need to be higher up.
>> All right. Put a one in the chat if you
could hear us pretty well.
>> Hopefully that's better.
Okay.
So, um
All right. Good. We got a good number of
people on already.
>> Yes. All right.
>> Um so, we know that you all are probably
looking for not probably, you should
definitely be looking forward to this
study. Um we need to pray. We need to
ask God to give us uh wisdom.
>> Amen. And uh we're going to go ahead
guys and jump in because this is going
to be a a very packed study tonight. So
uh we're going to go ahead and pray and
uh Tante, I'm going to
>> ask you to pray. And has literally no
idea.
>> I am with you guys. I mean, I know a
maybe a little bit more than you do, but
just a little. Just a very little. Yeah.
So, we're learning together.
>> So, let's bow our heads in prayer. Okay.
Heavenly Father, Lord, we want to thank
you for the Sabbath. Lord, I know some
are just either they're still not maybe
not here yet because they're still a
part of the 10 days of prayer that's
happening um around the world with the
Seventh Day Adventist Church and want to
thank you for that, Lord. And just thank
you that we are all here together uh to
learn uh together. We ask that your holy
spirit would guide this study and
discussion tonight in Jesus name. Amen.
>> Amen. Amen. Okay, guys. So, um we are
going to be doing a lot of reading
tonight. We're going to be doing a lot
of reading tonight. A lot of a lot of
quotes.
Um and a lot to share, a lot to talk
about. Um
so,
tonight's study is entitled
I've entitled it the 10th hour. The 10th
hour. Now, you might be wondering, "Wait
a minute. Pastor said we're going to be
talking about the T horns." And that is
correct. We are going to be talking
about the 10 horns of Daniel chapter 7.
[cough and clears throat]
But um we are going to be um titling
this message
uh the 10th hour. And you will see why
as we move forward in the message. Okay.
Um so let me go to my shared screen. Uh
let me click on presentation mode and
[clears throat and cough]
we are going to begin going to begin. So
we're going to start with Daniel chapter
2. Daniel chapter 2 um is uh the
prophecy of where Nebuchadnezzar has a
dream
>> and in that dream he sees a head of
gold, chest and arms of se silver, belly
and thighs of brass,
>> legs of iron and then toes of iron and
clay. Then he sees a stone that is cut
out without hands that destroys the
image on its feet. I want to read to you
Daniel 2:40 which says this. And as the
fourth kingdom shall be strong as iron,
[cough] for as much as iron breakth in
pieces, and subdueth all things, and as
iron that breakth all these shall it
break in pieces, and bruise.
And where thou sawst the feet and toes
part of potter's clay, and part of iron,
the kingdom shall be divided, but there
shall be in it [cough and clears throat]
of the strength of the iron. For as much
as you saw the iron mixed with my recay,
And as the toes of feet were partly iron
and partly clay, so the kingdom shall be
sharply strong.
Let me let me go back here for a second.
Okay. So the kingdom shall be partly
strong and partly broken.
I I think we just read that. So I'm
going to go ahead and move to the next
verse. And in the days of these kings
shall the God of heaven set up a kingdom
which shall never be destroyed. And the
kingdom shall not be left to other
people, but it shall break in pieces and
consume all these kingdoms, and it shall
stand forever. It shall stand forever.
So, um what [clears throat] we have here
is a description of what happens after
the fall of Rome. Okay. Now, um, put a
one in the chat if you have been taught
that these 10 toes,
uh, ultimately
represent
um, Europe, just go ahead and put a one
in the chat. If you've been taught that
these 10, the 10 toes of Daniel 2, we're
getting to Daniel 7 in a moment, but the
10 toes of Daniel 2 equals Europe. And
as an extension then
that the 10 toes of Daniel 2 is partly
um the United Nations.
So put a one in the chat if you've heard
that.
>> I've heard that.
>> Put a two in the chat if you have never
heard that. Okay. If you've never heard
that, great. If you've never heard that,
great. However, um most of you have
probably heard that Daniel 2 when uh
with these uh broken down kingdoms, they
represent
um Europe and then some take it a step
further and say it represents the United
Nations.
>> So, um here is what I want to show you.
Okay. Uh first of all, first of all, the
the the toes of iron and clay
um symbolize something.
Um in in Daniel, I'm sorry, in Isaiah
chapter 64:8, the Bible says, "But now,
O Lord, thou art our father. We are the
clay and thou are potter, and we are all
the work of thy hand."
>> [clears throat]
>> In the Bible, clay is used to symbolize
the professed people of God.
>> So when we look at Babylon and then Meet
Persia and then Greece and then Rome, we
see that these are secular kingdoms.
>> Okay? But the the the stone that is cut
out without hands destroys the image.
Not in the head, not in the chest and
arms,
>> not in the belly and thighs, not in the
legs of iron,
>> but on the toes of iron and clay.
Meaning that is the most offensive part
of this image to God. So think about
this. Think about Babylon.
>> Mixing.
>> Yeah. Think about Babylon, me, Persia,
Greece, Rome. God is like, I'll bear
that. I'll bear that. I'll bear that.
But when we get to the toes of iron and
clay,
>> this is where the stone destroys the
image. Why?
Because if the iron represents state
power and the clay represents church
power,
>> then what we have is a mingling of
church and state
>> and that is what is offensive to God.
>> Right?
>> Okay. That's what offensive is offensive
to God. So this these 10 the toes of
iron and clay symbolize
the mingling of church and state. Now,
I've been studying this prophecy for
um
>> uh 31 maybe years.
>> So, close there. 31
>> years.
>> 31 years.
>> 30 years. 30 years plus.
>> And I have never stopped to think
what what I'm about to share with you
tonight. It just
>> and I'm just like, "Wow, how how how did
how did I miss this?
>> How did we miss this?
>> These
um kingdoms,
first of all, like maybe first bombshell
is this. These kingdoms extend, let me
show you. Notice with me the book of
Revelation chapter 6 verse14
>> which says um and the the and the
heavens departed as a scroll when it is
rolled together and every mountain and
island were moved out of their place and
the kings of the earth and the great men
and the rich men and the chief captains
and the mighty men and every bondman and
every free man hid themselves in the
dens and in the rocks of the mountains
and said unto the mountains and rocks
fall on us and hide us from the face of
him that siteth on the throne and from
the wrath of the lamb, for the great day
of his wrath is come. And who shall be
able to stand? The question that we have
is this.
When that stone that is cut out without
hands is headed towards the earth, to
destroy the earth, um is it coming to
destroy Europe? So, put a one in the
chat if your answer is yes, that stone
in Daniel 2 is coming to destroy Europe.
Because if the toes of iron and clay
only represent Europe,
>> then that would mean that when Jesus
returns, he's coming to destroy Europe.
>> Mhm.
>> Obviously, this is not true.
>> In Revelation chapter 6, we have the
kings of the earth are present at the
second coming of Jesus,
>> which matches Daniel chapter 2. When the
stone comes, the kings of the earth, in
the days of these kings, the text says,
>> in the days of these kings shall the
king of heaven set up a kingdom.
>> So whatever happens, we know that
Jesus is not coming back to destroy
Europe. He's coming back to destroy the
whole world.
>> Which means that these 10 k these
kingdoms must represent more than
Europe. They must come to represent the
whole world. All right, y'all put a five
in the chat if that makes sense so far.
Because what this does immediately what
this does, beloved,
is that it removes
any
special
place in prophecy
>> that
lands on Europe or the United Nations.
Mhm.
>> Daniel 2 is not talking about the United
Nations. It is not only talking about
Europe. It begins in Europe,
>> but it's going to grow to cover the
entire world. So by the end of time,
these 10 kingdoms represent the whole
world,
>> right?
>> It is the whole world
>> that is uniting against the stone that
is cut out without hands.
>> Okay? So, uh if that makes sense. so
far. Uh go ahead. I'm seeing the fives
in the chat. We have we have settled on
Daniel chapter 2. And then I need to
share something else about Daniel
chapter 2.
>> What we need to understand about Daniel
chapter 2 is this.
Daniel chapter 2
is the story
of corrupt Christianity
as it is manifested through these t
horns.
>> Okay,
>> so let me say that again because that is
probably going to be a new thought for
many of you.
>> Corrupt Christianity in each
phasing.
>> Each of these 10 horns
>> will will represent a corrupted
state of Christianity.
So think of it like this, right? You got
Babylon, Mipers Persia, Greece, Rome.
These are all secular uh nations,
secular kingdoms,
>> right?
>> In the time of Rome, you have Jesus.
Mhm.
>> Jesus comes and he's going to
preach the gospel and he's going to
start a movement which is designed to
convert
hearts.
>> Now listen to what I just said. The
gospel Jesus preaches will be designed
to convert individual
human [snorts] hearts.
Nothing more, nothing less.
>> Right?
>> What we find in Daniel chapter 2 is not
the conversion
of hearts, but the conversion of
nations.
>> All right, I'mma ask just see if you
y'all following with me. Put a one in
the chat if you're following with me.
Let me tell you why this is so
important.
Because nations, you guys, cannot be
converted,
>> right?
>> We have already set the foundation to
understand something that I just never
saw before. Maybe others have seen it
before. Maybe I'll just be excited by
myself. But whoa. The reason that these
kingdoms
are described is because they all
are various manifestations
>> of what happens when you mingle church
and state. M
>> everybody put a put a five in the chat
once again if you're like wow like
>> that makes s I've never thought about
that before put a five in the chat if
you've never thought about that before
>> because I'll tell you what happens right
>> what we have done
>> with go ahead
>> that's how they fell I mean to mix the
two together
>> every one of them
>> is a representation of iron and clay
>> it's not that summer iron
>> and summer clay Okay.
>> But all 10 of them as we walk through
these 10 kings, these 10 kingdoms, we're
going to see stuff that's going to blow
your mind.
>> That's what we're going to do tonight,
right?
And and let me tell you why this is so
important. Because we understand in
Daniel chapter 2, oh, Daniel 2 is about
the mingling of iron and clay, but we
limit that mingling of iron and clay
>> to the papacy,
>> right?
>> The 11th horn. when we get to Daniel
chapter 7. So, let's go to Daniel
chapter 7, guys. Let's go to Daniel
chapter 7 and um
okay, pull it up on the screen here and
I need to go back. Okay, so Daniel
chapter 7, right? So, Daniel 7, we have
four kingdoms again.
>> Lion, bear, leopard,
>> fourth nondescript beast. Okay? And then
we have out of that fourth beast, we've
got 10 horns,
>> right?
>> And then we've got a little horn. So
Daniel 7 verse 7. After after this I saw
in the night visions, and behold, a
fourth beast, dreadful and terrible, and
strong exceedingly, and it had great
iron teeth. It devoured and break in
pieces, and stamped the residue with the
feet of it. And it was diverse from all
the beasts that were before it. And it
had 10 horns.
And I considered the horns, and behold,
there came up among them another little
horn,
before whom there were three of the
first horns plucked up by the roots. And
behold, in this horn were the eyes like
the eyes of a man, and a mouth speaking
great things. Okay. So what we typically
do when we study Daniel chapter 7 is our
attention is locked in on that 11th horn
>> and we're like, "Oh, this is where you
have the mingling of church and state.
It's in the papacy,
>> right?
>> Which is correct."
>> We may go as far as to recognize the
three horns that were uprooted,
right? the Ostrogoths, the Vandals, and
the
>> Hereli.
>> Oh, so those three horns were uprooted
and and that's how we know that it's the
papacy. And we typically stop there.
>> We may go on to say, "Yeah, you know
what? Uh, and the other horns were the
Savvi and the Alamnei and the Ostrogo, I
mean the the um the uh Burgundians." and
we'll just go through the list, the
Franks, and we'll say, "Yeah, those
those nations are are what we now know
today as" and we'll go through a list of
nations, right? But then we stop there.
>> That's it. That's a problem.
That's a problem.
Because
when we actually begin to look at these
horns and their history,
>> all of a sudden, alarm bells start going
off.
Let me mention something. I'm going to
mention this upfront here
because here's what I want us to
understand. There are a lot of people
there there are some people let me say
in in the church who are
anti-trinitarian
>> and they in fact someone asked a
question last night and it was an honest
question. Hey the papacy uprooted three
of the 10 horns because those three
horns were anti- trinitarian. So how can
we side with the papacy right in a
rooting I mean side with the papacy in
being trinitarian, which by the way,
Adventists do not believe the same thing
as the Catholic Church when it comes to
the Trinity, but that's a whole another
study for a whole another time.
>> But the question is, look at what they
did to these other three horns. Doesn't
that isn't that evidence that we should
be siding with those three horns? You
guys, here's the problem with that.
All 10 horns
represent corrupted Christianity. Y'all
put a 10 in the chat.
>> All 10 horns,
>> if you get what I'm saying. I'm I'm
saying that number 10 for a reason.
>> All ten horns
represent a version of corrupt
Christianity.
What is corrupt about them will differ.
And in a sense, what we're gonna find is
that it's all the same thing.
>> But to argue, well, the papacy uprooted
the Ostrogothos and the Visogos and the
Herili. Therefore, we should side with
the Ostrogothos and the and the and the
vandals and the Hereli. No, all 10 are
corrupt.
>> They were all cut from the same cloth.
They're all Babylon, Meopersia, Greece,
Rome, the T horns, the little horn, all
represent their part of the same system.
That's the point,
>> right?
>> Okay. So, it's now time for some
history.
>> Same spirit.
>> Same spirit. It's now time for some
history. So, again,
it may be a new thought. Whoa. So you're
saying, pastor, that all t horns
represent counterfeit versions of
Christianity. Think about this. In the
Roman Empire, you now have two things
going forward. the true gospel
>> which was preached by Jesus
>> in which hearts are to be converted
>> and then a counterfeit gospel that
mingles
iron
with clay
>> and ends up
in the conversion
the conversion
of nations
whole nations.
How does that happen? Mhm.
>> How do how do you convert
a whole nation?
And then when you see the means by which
they were converted, you're going to be
like, "Oh, wow. Never saw this before."
>> So, here's what we're going to do.
Before we get to the T horns, we need to
go to the template. Okay? So, let me
just see. Make sure everybody's
following. Y'all put a put a one in the
chat.
>> Want to make sure we're all on the same
page so far. put a one in the chat.
One in the chat. I want to make sure
that we're following. And now we're
going to go to the template, you guys.
So remember, um there's a time that
Christianity is is a persecuted power.
It's a persecuted power.
>> And then something h in the Roman
Empire. And then something happens. The
conversion of Constantine.
Constantine becomes the template.
So let me read the f the phrase inhawk
signal vinces translates to in this sign
thou shalt conquer and is associated
with Constantine the great.
>> It is believed that before the battle of
Milvian Milvian bridge in 312 AD
Constantine experienced a vision of a
cross in the sky accompanied by the
inscription. This vision was interpreted
as a divine message leading him to order
his soldiers to inscribe crosses on
their shields which ultimately resulted
in his victory over his rival Maxentius.
All right. So I want you to note what
happens here.
Constantine
converts
for military purposes.
Put a one. You guys let
two in the chat if that is genuine
conversion. Three in the chat if that is
counterfeit conversion.
>> What do what do you think?
>> Counterfeit.
>> Counterfeit conversion.
>> That's a counterfeit conversion.
>> You actually command your soldiers to
put crosses on their seals.
>> So now everybody's Christian,
>> right? And here you have in Constantine
the very first
template of what happens [clears throat]
when church and state mingle because now
all of a sudden everybody's converted.
>> Wait a minute. Everybody's converted.
You mean Jesus came to everybody and
talked to them and someone witnessed it?
No. When Constantine converted,
everybody followed. Mhm.
>> It wasn't a personal experience,
>> a relationship.
>> It wasn't a relationship. It was based
on political
>> expediency.
>> Mhm.
>> I want you to note that phrase. In this
sign shalt thou conquer.
The cross
and conquering don't go together. Mm-m.
>> This very concept
stated by Constantine in the cross you
will conquer becomes the the template
that we will see is used
by all ten horns.
>> They follow Constantine's lead including
the papacy.
So in other words, [clears throat]
when we look at Constantine and we see
in the sign, you're going to conquer
militarily, politically, stop right
there, everybody.
Do you do you can you look at what's
going on today
in the Christian world
and see that very phrase
being accepted by the Christian world
today.
>> In this sign behind the cross, the
shield of the cross, we will defeat our
enemies. We will conquer.
So
this is Constantine
>> 321 Christianity becomes uh legalized in
Rome. And I want you to see what Ellen
White has to say on this. The nominal
conversion of Constantine in the early
part of the 4th century. Put that word
nominal in the chat for me, please.
Nominal. Nominal. Nominal. The nominal
conversion of Constantine in the early
part of the 4th century caused great
rejoicing and the world cloaked with a
form of righteousness walked into the
church. Now the work of corruption
rapidly progressed. Paganism while
appearing to be vanquished became the
conqueror. Her spirit controlled the
church. her doctrines, ceremonies and
superstitions were incorporated into the
faith and worship at of and worship of
the professed followers of Christ. So
now we have a nominal conversion that
leads to
thousands of nominal conversions,
>> right?
>> Rome
has now been Christianized.
Only problem is you can't Christianize a
nation,
>> right?
>> A nation doesn't get Christianized.
People get Christianized.
>> It's an individual thing.
All right. So,
in fact, let me finish reading this
statement. This compromise between
paganism and Christianity resulted in
the development of the man of sin
foretold in prophecy as opposing and
exalting exalting himself above God.
This gigantic system of false religion
is a masterpiece of Satan's power. A
monument of the efforts to seat himself
upon the throne to rule the earth
according to his will. All right. So,
so
uh what we have here,
what we have here [snorts] is a
description,
me pull this. What we have here, guys,
is a description of how the papacy
actually
begins. This is the start of the man of
sin, right?
mingling of church and state. Okay, with
that said, now I'm going to show you
something. Let's go to Revelation
chapter 17 verse 12. Revelation chapter
17 and verse 12. And here, chapter 17
verse 12. Here's what the Bible says. It
says, "And the 10 horns which thou
sawest are 10 kings which have received
no kingdom as yet.
but receive power as kings, one hour
with the beast.
These have one mind, and shall give
their power and strength unto the beast.
These shall make war with the Lamb, and
the Lamb shall overcome them, for he is
the Lord of Lords, and King of Kings,
and they that are with him are called
chosen and faithful. Okay.
So, um, each of these horns,
each of these horns rules with the beast
for one hour. The Bible also says that
when John is writing, he says, "These
have received no kingdom as of yet."
Now, why is John saying this? Because at
the time he's writing, he is in the
Roman Empire.
>> Meaning the T horns are yet future.
Everybody got that?
>> Because
>> the T horns are yet future.
>> So in other words, what he's saying is
each one of these horns is going to rule
in the same time with the beast.
These 10 horns
are each going to have their time, their
hour, their era with the beast.
Notice Revelation 14:6. The Bible says
here, "And I saw another angel fly in
the midst of heaven, having the
everlasting gospel to preach unto them
that dwell on the earth, and to every
nation, kindred, tongue, and people.
saying with loud voice, fear God and
give glory to him for the hour of his
judgment has come. So that hour of
judgment is not a it's not a specific
time period.
>> It's talking about an extended period of
time, whatever that time might be,
>> right?
>> Go ahead.
>> I'm saying so the like what you said
before, the beast was consistent through
every
throughout all of them.
>> So the beast is present through all
these horns, right? Each one of these
horns, it's almost as if each one of
these horns has their time with the
beast.
They have their their stage with the
>> You know, I I don't know for well for me
since I'm learning with everybody else
here, it's like when you've when you've
looked at this study in the past, it's
like you never think of the beast
throughout all of them consistent. Does
that make sense? Like when you think of
well you first of all you're just always
thinking about the papacy for the most
part.
>> So here's what we think. We say okay so
you got the 10 the 10 horns and then the
rise of the papacy right
>> and with the rise of the papacy we're
not even focused on the on the 10 horns
anymore. We've just forgotten about
them. I mean I'm almost 52 almost at 51
and I've never really looked I mean I'
and been raised in the church and been
to many Revelation seminars and I've
never or Daniel revelation and never
thought about it that way.
>> Yeah. So that's what we're going to do
tonight. We're actually going to go,
okay, so if these 10 horns all rule at
some point with the beast, then
how are we going to um how are we going
to to understand, right?
>> How these ten horns play out and why God
is showing us these ten horns. That is
key. That is crucial.
All right, so are y'all ready? We're
going to begin.
>> God doesn't waste.
>> Like there's everything is in the Bible
for a reason. So
>> we should expect that they
>> It means something.
>> So hour one, right? And this is this is
just me painting the picture and I'm
using these terms. The Bible doesn't use
hour one, hour two, but I'm I'm simply
just showing the connection between each
horn, but I'm showing it in a
chronological way. Okay? So the 10th
hour
is going to be the 10th horn.
>> I hope y'all are prepared.
I hope y'all are prepared. Okay,
so horn number one,
the
>> Hereli.
>> This is one of the horns that were
uprooted. The king is Odasser.
And here's what it says. Odasser, the
leader of the Hereli, was the first of
the barbarians who reigned over the
Romans. He took the throne of Italy
according to Gibbon um according to
Gibbon in decline and fall of the Roman
Empire volume 3 page 510 and 5:15 in 476
of his religion of his religious belief.
Gibbon says like the rest of the
barbarians he had been instructed in the
Aryan heresy but he was revered but he
revered the mon the mon the monastic and
episcopal characters and the silence of
the Catholics attest the toleration
which they enjoyed. Again
he says quote the Ostrogs, the
Burgundians, the Suvi and the Vandals
who had who had uh listed listen to the
eloquence of the Latin clergy preferred
the more intelligible lessons of their
domestic teachers and Aryanism was
adopted as the national faith.
the national faith
>> of the warlike converts who were seated
on the ruins of the western empire. This
er irreconcilable difference of religion
was a persistent source of jealousy and
hatred and the reproach of barbarian of
barbarian and the reproach of barbarian
was embittered by the more odious epitth
of heretic.
This Uriah Smith Daniel revelation. So
what he's saying here is that this first
king Hereli the the Heralai kingdom
Odasser
>> Mhm.
>> was converted to Christianity
and in that conversion
the entire
tribe
kingdom as it were was converted. So
listen to this.
Because of the conversion of their
leader,
then everybody underneath them had to
become what the leader was. So the
reason that the Herili are Aryan
>> is because the conversion was based on a
single individual,
>> right?
>> Does that make sense everybody?
>> Yeah. So it was not a real conversion.
>> It's not a real conversion.
>> It's corrupt conversion.
>> It's corrupt conversion. What God is
showing us in this first horn is, "All
right, guys. I'm going to show you what
happens when you pervert Christianity.
>> When you pervert Christianity,
what happens
is not actually Christianity."
Right.
>> No. Right. You now have an entire
conversion of a of a and the conversion
of an where we are all like Constantine
when Constantine says okay here's what I
am and he commands all his soldiers to
put you know um crosses on their shields
this is force conversion
>> which is not what Jesus was ever about
>> now you guys
as I am breaking down these 10 horns I
need you to be thinking about our time
and today.
>> I've been thinking
>> just keep thinking about this.
>> Keep thinking about what's happening
today in our time. What is prophesied to
happen at the end of time?
>> So what we see in the in the the horn,
the Herili horn is with the conversion
of their king from pagan to Aryan,
the entire nation becomes Aryan. Mhm.
>> And even though they were they were
against the Catholic Church in the sense
that they were Aryan,
>> this is a very Catholic principle,
>> iron
and clay mingling
to produce
forced conversion,
>> right? State conversion,
>> okay, so we're going to go back to the
screen. We're going to go now to the
second hour. Let's talk about the
Vandals.
So, the king, the Vandals, his name was
Jenser.
And it says here, the Vandals adopted
Aryan Christianity as well. Uh their
power was at its height when Jenniseric
died in 477. In his time, the Vandals
became Christians, but they were Aryans
and fiercely persecuted Orthodox
believers and other heretics. In 533 the
bisonantine general Belliserius landed
in Africa and it goes on to explain how
you know how they were uprooted.
>> But again what you see in the vandal
horn is with the conversion of their
king
>> with the conversion of their king you
now have the v uh the conversion of the
entire people.
>> We are Aryan right? We are we've moved
from paganism to Christianity. We're all
Christian now.
>> Now again, you guys,
>> the the point I want to show you here is
that what is happening and what you're
going to see happening in each of these
10 horns in what I call their hour,
>> right?
>> So, some of them had shorter hours, some
of them you're going to see have longer
hours.
>> But in their time, the thing that kind
of that God is saying, look at this.
Look at this with this horn. Look at
this with this horn. Look at this with
this horn. You're going to see a
consistent theme
>> throughout
>> these 10 horns.
>> Okay.
So, let's go to the Ostrogothic horn.
And in the Ostrogothic horn,
you have Theodoric the Great. The
Ostrogothic Papacy was a significant
period in the history of the papacy
marked by the influence of the
Ostrogothic Kingdom on the papacy's
selection and administration. In other
words, uh let me just let me explain
this more briefly. The Ostrogothic horn
with the conversion of their king um
they were they were Aryan but they ruled
over they were the ones choosing the pap
choosing the pope the popes for the
papacy
>> and in 538
that comes to an end. You now have a new
line alliance. So when Justinian um um
uh when the when the Ostrogoths are
defeated and Justinian's decree is
implemented, you now have a new line of
popes, bisentinian popes, no longer
Ostrogothic popes. However, don't get
confused in all that. What I'm saying is
this.
>> The Ostrogos are in their rule with the
papacy,
>> they're controlling
>> who they want to be the pope.
Mhm.
>> And so remember, it is after this is
done away with that the papacy begins
its 1,260
year rule.
>> But what I'm showing you is that in the
Ostrogothic kingdom, in the Herili
kingdom, which also was uh which also
partnered with the papacy to a certain
degree, with the exception of the
Vandals who fought against the papacy.
What you're seeing is that in all three
horns that are uprooted,
they all represent different versions of
corrupted Christianity
for the purpose of political gain and
territorial gain.
>> Does that make sense? Everybody put a
one in the chat if you're following so
far. If you're like, "Okay, this makes
sense." So they were using corrupt using
corrupt Christianity
>> but it looked like it was Christianity
but it was corrupt Christianity. They
were using that to you said territorial
or
>> they were using Christianity for
political gain which makes it corrupt.
>> Let me say it again
>> for those of you sitting in the back.
They were using
Christianity
>> as a means to political power
>> which corrupts Christianity.
Okay. Now these three horns end up being
uprooted by the papacy
>> because they were standing in the way of
what the papacy is trying to accomplish.
>> Okay. And by the way, Aryanism
was really just a
an excuse used by the papacy to conquer
those territories. It wasn't really
they're Aryans and we just hate Aryans,
meaning they were against, you know,
they believe that Jesus had a beginning.
>> These were pretenses to gain territory.
>> Yeah. Someone has said the song remains
the same. Absolutely. The song remains
the same. I need to go to the fourth
horn. And as we get to each horn, guys,
you're going to you're going to begin to
see clearer clearer and clearer like,
oh, wait a minute. So, the fourth horn
or we will say the fourth hour is the
Franks. That's another horn.
>> The king of of the of the Franks is
Clovis.
Um and this is um I believe this is at
Jones writing when he says this he's
describing the history of of the Franks
and Clovis. It is said that the
conversion of Clovis gave rise to the
custom of addressing the French monarch
with the title of most Christian majesty
>> and the eldest son of the church. For
the kings of the other barbarious
nations which occupy the Roman provinces
were still addicted to idolatry or
involved in the errors of Aryanism.
>> So Clovis
um is the first king to convert and
become Catholic.
>> Okay. So now what you're going to see in
the clo in the in the Frankish Empire is
what happens
when you connect with the papacy. And
what what happened is that the Franks
became the sword of the papacy. That's
how the other three horns ended up
getting uprooted.
>> The Franks became the first military, if
you will, of the papacy.
So now in the Franks, you see another
version of what happens. It's almost as
if God is saying this. I'm going to show
you 10 different ways that Christianity
gets corrupted. As you look at these 10
horns, I'm going to show you 10
>> versions of corrupt Christianity.
>> Christianity for political gain.
>> When Christianity becomes militarized,
that's what we see in the Frankish horn,
>> right? Christianity has now become
militarized
and now the papacy can begin
persecuting.
>> Is that going to happen
>> in the name of God?
>> In the name of God, is that going to
happen at the end of time everybody?
>> Yes.
Just looking at the four horns that
we've already studied in, you know, just
at a surface level,
>> can we safely say, hm, we know that at
the end of time, whatever this 10th hour
is,
we know that you are I I see you. We
know um yeah, we know
that these 10 that these
the things that happened in these
previous horns
are going to
again happen at the end of time.
>> Okay.
So, are y'all following so far?
>> Are we good so far? Is this making sense
so far?
Let me go back to the screen and I want
you to check out Clovis's conversion.
>> Uh, Clovis
is on a battlefield.
He's in the midst of a fight of a battle
>> and he basically does the same thing as
Constantine. He says if we win this
battle we will convert. And what you
know we how do you say
>> we will convert.
>> So they win this battle. Clovis converts
>> and again you have an entire nation
converting. Here's the problem you guys.
Let me come back to here is the problem.
How do you convert nations?
You cannot convert. The gospel is about
converting individuals.
>> Yes.
>> By free will. It's not well the leader
converted so now we must convert. And
this is what we see happening in these
first four horns. We see if the leader
converts then we become what the leader
is.
>> Which is not actual Christianity.
>> No, it's not real conversion. you know,
just I mean, I know we're just, you
know, starting off and still have a lot
to go, but
>> it's just showing me that
>> Satan is not creative. He just does the
same thing over and over and over again.
He He hasn't stopped doing the same
play. Yep.
>> He just runs the same play.
>> Yep. Absolutely. Absolutely. All right.
Now, we're going to go to the fifth
horn.
>> We're going to go to the fifth hour. The
fifth hour. So the fifth hour and the
fifth horn is the Burgundians
>> and uh this is what would represent
today's Switzerland,
>> right? So Franks will be France,
Burgundians would be Switzerland. Um and
here's what it says. The same principle
and the king is a king by the name of
Gund Gondad.
And here's what it says of this.
Uh this same principle was clearly
stated by the Catholic bishop Avidus
when the Aryan king Gundabad appealed to
him not to allow the Catholic king
Clovis which we just read about
>> to overrun his country. Avidus answered,
"If Gundabad would reconcile himself to
the church, the church would guarantee
his safety from the attacks of Clovis."
>> Gundabbad ends up converting
as does all his followers,
>> right?
>> For protection.
>> You guys, do you see this?
Becoming a follower of Jesus
in order to receive protection from
another military, from another power,
from another kingdom is not actual
conversion.
>> Right. You join their religious belief
system. Absolutely. For protection.
>> And Clovis still went and conquered that
territory.
>> Wow.
>> So again, whoa. What we're looking at
here, guys, so far
is that in these five horns, we're
looking at five different versions of
corrupted Christianity.
>> We're looking at five different versions
of what happens when clay and iron
mingle together.
>> They don't mingle together.
>> They can't mingle together.
Okay. So, so far we've seen, wow, we got
five five horns and five of them
false Christianity. [music]
False Christianity.
Okay.
What is the next horn?
So, the next horn is the Lombards.
This is would be what is Italy today.
The king is Agalof also known as the
Thor the Thoringian
or the Thingian was a significant figure
in the lum in Lumbard history. He became
king in 591 and was influenced by his
wife Theodinda who was a Catholic under
her influence Aguil converted to
Catholicism around 603 marking a pivotal
shift in the Lumbard kingdom's religious
landscape. His reign was marked by
consolidating Lumbard control and
maintaining peace with the papacy and
other powers which laid the groundwork
for the kingdom's future. So again,
here you have the conversion of a king
leads to
the conversion of the entire kingdom.
It's almost like you're seeing this
repeat like whoa it this is the same
thing over and over again. It's the same
principle happening. You can't
convert nations.
>> God didn't say he said go and preach to
all nations, right? But he didn't say
convert the nations. He said go and
preach to all nations. Meaning you're
supposed to be going and speaking to the
people.
>> Kingdoms don't convert.
>> People convert.
>> But there's something else about the
lumbars I want you to see.
Um,
and we're on the sixth hour. So here
here I want you to see this. Uh so
there's another king called Luitt Prand
who is also the Lumbards who comes a
little bit later. King Lu PR's reign
marked a pivotal moment for the Lumbards
as they largely competed completed their
transition to Catholic Christianity
under his rule. He actively strengthened
ties with the Roman church, solidifying
a religious shift that would have
lasting implications for the kingdom's
identity and its relationship with the
papacy.
Um the by Luran's reign by Luran's reign
the Lumbard's elite the Lumbard elite
and many of the people were converted to
Catholicism removing a major religious
obstacle to integration with the Latin
population of Italy. Lucapan also played
a key political role by recognizing,
listen to this now, papal territory
claims in central Italy, most famously
through the donation of sutri, a
political act that helped lay the
foundation for papal temporal power.
What is the doctrine of sutri or what is
donation of sutri? The donation of sutri
occurred during a time when the Lumbards
were transitioning from Aryanism to
Catholicism. Luchapan facing internal
challenges and the need for political
stability sought to strengthen his
position by aligning with the papacy.
This agreement was was reached at Sutri
where L where Lubrand granted the city
and several hi and several hill towns in
in Latium including veta to the papacy
as a gift to the blessed apostle Peter
and Paul according to the liber
pontipico.
Basically,
these were the grounds that would become
that would become the papal states
>> that would become the Vatican.
>> And now in this six horn, the Lumbards,
you see, oh, their reign, their hour is
what provided the territory,
the Vatican territory for the papacy.
the Papal States now is under them going
to become
an official
church state
>> plot of land. And now you're like, whoa,
okay,
[snorts] six horns so far and all of
them are lending
or showing the results. God never told
the church to set up a kingdom on earth.
>> He never told the church to set up It it
the papacy is not uh the Vatican is not
um
the center of God's you know uh place on
earth. It's not the center of the
kingdom of God on earth.
>> But corrupt Christianity has to have
something to worship
>> right.
>> It's idolatry.
It's idolatry.
So again, what you're seeing through
these horns
>> is how each one of them played a part,
played a role
in
corrupting
>> Christianity.
>> All right.
Now, it's time for us
to uh
to take a deep breath.
>> Okay? is we have four horns left, you
guys. Uh we're on horn number six. We
got horn number seven, eight, nine, and
10.
>> And you guys, it's going to get pretty
intense. It's going to get pretty
intense. We're going to go to hour
seven. We're going to go to horn seven.
Put a one in the chat. Put a seven in
the chat if you are ready for what
you're about to hear. Put a one in the
chat if you are not ready for what
you're about to hear.
Um let's go. Let's go. So the seventh
horn
is the Suevi kingdom. The suvi kingdom
it's also known as Portugal which will
be Portugal today. The territory is
Portugal today.
>> The king is the is Theodmer
and the conversion is a Catholic
conversion.
their hour we're going to focus on
something called the doctrine of
discovery. The doctrine of discovery. So
let's let's see what this is about. So
in the 1400s
um the papacy issues a series of bulls.
Uh one of them is called dum dum diver.
Dumb deverus in 1452 authorized the king
of Portugal to subjugate
um sariss and pagans and reduce them to
servitude
in the name of Jesus. M
>> the ro the Romanus pont pontifffects
expanded Portugal's right to conquer and
trade in non-Christian lands especially
in West Africa.
The intercatera issued after Columbus's
voyages granting Spain rights to lands
west of the demarcation line and to
spread Christianity there. And we're
going to come back to Columbus in a
moment. And then um the dudum sequum
let's begin with reinforced or [music]
clarified for more things territorial
grants. So people bulls about
>> not for specifically regarding Portugal
>> but for his
>> in the name of Christianity they were
now able to go and conquer other
people's lands
>> and if you were not Christian
uh that gave uh Portugal a right to
subjugate you in the name of Jesus
to convert you as a Christian. M
>> in other words [clears throat]
in this seventh horn you now have
another picture of corrupt Christianity
>> which is I can go and take other
people's lands.
I have the right, we have the right as
believers, as Christians, righteousness
by forth, by force. Yep. We have the
right to go and conquer other people's
lands. So, it was because of these
bulls. These bulls gave permission then
for Portugal to actually go and begin
conquering other lands.
>> Um, this would include the transatlantic
slave trade.
Whoa,
wait a minute. The transatlantic slave
trade is the result is what we get when
you corrupt Christianity,
>> military by force,
>> um uh political uh
>> Christianity for political uh gain
>> and thinking you're more super than
other. And now because you're a
Christian,
you have a right to go take other
people's lands.
This is documented
Christian stuff, you guys.
And what God is showing us in these 10
horns in the seven that we've seen so
far and now in this seventh horn
>> is woe.
>> This is what corrupt Christianity does.
>> Corrupt Christianity takes other
people's lands.
The reason that that we need to
understand this you guys is because I'm
what I'm going to share with you beloved
is that in that 10th hour
that 10th horn basically what we're
going to see
is that a combination of all of the
things that came before will be
manifested in that final
hour.
Y'all put a put a eight in the chat if
you understand
what I just said. The reason we're going
through these horns one by one and
seeing here's what corrupt Christianity
did with the Herili. Here's what it did
with the Ostrots. Here's what it did
with the Vandals. Here's what it did
with the Burgundians. Here's what it did
with the Franks. Here's what it did with
the Swayi. The reason we're doing that
is because
what God is trying to show us, I
believe, is why the time of trouble,
such as never was, will be.
>> What the final iteration
of counterfeit Christianity is going to
look like is a combination of everything
we saw in the horns before it.
I'm seeing a whole bunch of eights. So,
excellent. Excellent. Now, you
[clears throat] will remember
that Columbus in 1492, I want you to
note this. Let me go back here. So,
these decrees 1452, 1493, 1493, 1455.
Remember it is in 1492 that Columbus
discovers
America.
>> He landed on America.
>> He landed on
>> that was already discovered.
>> And he does so under the the directions
of Spain,
>> which is one of the 10 horns, y'all.
So now I want you to begin to think of
the connection between the the eighth
horn
that's the visog the
>> visots.
>> This is the Spain. This is what is now
what we would now call today Spain.
Are y'all following?
>> So they have a king that converts to
Catholicism in around 589. But what is
their hour? What is their hour? You
might remember something called the
Spanish Inquisitions.
>> The Spanish Inquisition was established
by King Ferdinandu of Araggon and Queen
Elizabeth Isabella the 1 of Castile on
November 1st, 1478.
It aimed to consolidate power in the
newly unified Spanish kingdom by
enforcing [snorts]
religious conformity. There we go again.
Wow. Everywhere we look in these ten
horns, it's the same thing, the
enforcing
of Christianity.
>> But in the Spanish Inquisition, it goes
on to say here um um religious
conformity, particularly targeting those
who had converted from Judaism and Islam
to Catholicism. M
>> the Inquisition intensified following
royal decrees in 1492 and 1501 which
ordered Jews and Muslims to either
convert or face expulsion from Spain.
This led to the forced conversion of
many and the expulsion of approximately
160,000 Jews from the country hour by
hour Clint hour by hour.
the the the the Spanish Inquisition
now shows us, hey, here is another
picture of what happens when you corrupt
Christianity.
>> Corrupt Christianity leads to the
Spanish Inquisition,
>> man.
So, as I'm looking at these horns,
the
use of
religion for political gain,
converting for protection,
>> um using uh
religion with a sword, that's the
Franks.
A religion where you can go and take
other people's territory and enslave
them.
>> Portugal,
>> a religion where you can persecute and
kill people that do not believe as you
believe. And if they die
or if they are killed not being
Christian, then it doesn't matter. Mhm.
>> But if they're Christian, then it does
matter.
>> If they're not Christian,
they don't deserve to be spoken of well
at all. But if they are Christian, you
better talk about them well.
>> Wow.
So, as we look at these first eight
horns or these first eight hours, we're
seeing, whoa,
>> God, are you showing us? Are you showing
us what the final iteration of
Christianity is going to look like?
Is this what you're telling us? All
right.
Um, by the way, by the way, check this
out, you guys. Here's what Ellen White
says in the Acts of the Apostles, page
84. The same spirit which in the dark
ages consigned men and women to prison,
to exile, and to death, which conceived
the exquisite torture of the
Inquisition,
which conce uh which planned and
executed the massacre of St. Bartholomew
>> and which kindled the fires of
Smithfield is still at work with
malignant energy in unregenerate hearts.
>> The history of truth has ever been the
record of the struggle between right and
wrong. The proclamation of the gospel
has ever been carried forward in this
world in the face of opposition, peril,
and suffering. In other words, what
she's saying here [clears throat]
is really that the same spirit that you
found in the Spanish Inquisition
>> is still present with us today. If
that's true about the Spanish
Inquisition, what about the Franks?
What about the
>> Suei?
What about um what about uh um the
Braundians?
>> What about all these other horns? The
same spirit I believe
will be manifested in the final I'm
going to say it this way. The final
horn.
>> The final horn.
>> There's a tenth horn.
>> Wait. But I'm always focused on the
paper horn.
>> Right.
>> Hold on.
>> I
>> like I've heard I've heard all I've
heard mention of all of these um horns
before and they're you know they're
plucked up and and that's it. Like it's
just not I never understood this deep of
history about any of them. Consistency.
>> That's right. They're just plucked up
and we just move on cuz our focus is on
the little horn,
>> which is still the little horn and we
need to we need to know what what the
little horn is doing. But
>> yeah,
>> we need to understand all of this as
well.
>> All right, y'all.
Now, you're not going to believe what
I'm about to share with you next, but
I'm going share it anyway. So this is
still this is still the Spanish
Inquisition.
>> In the Spanish Inquisition, there was
something that was implemented that
dealt with blood purity. I'mma read it
to you. The statutes of blood purity
were based on the belief that the body's
fluid
and especially blood transmitted a
certain number of moral qualities from
parents to children. and that Jews as a
people were incapable of change despite
their conversion as stated by the fri by
frier uh prudencio de sandal I didn't
pronounce that name regarding the holy
and prudent blood purity statute of the
Toledo Cathedral of 1555 who which
served as a model for all subsequent
ones the statutes of blood purity were
based on the belief I'm Sorry.
Who can deny? So this is the
continuation. Who can deny that in the
descendants of Jews
persists and endures the inclination
to the evil of their ancient ingratitude
and ignorance. Just as in black people
the inseparable accident of their
blackness. A Jew may descend on three
sides from gentlemen or old Christians,
but a single bad lineage infects and on
the other hand it remains a subject of
debate whether the Iberian statutes of
blood purity were the origin of the more
of the modern European racism. According
to Jean Tajan Frederick Schwab, the
contribution of Iberian blood purity
statutes to the formation of racial
categories lies at the intersection of
personal exclusion
and collective stigmat stigmatization.
According to the Max Sebastian,
according to Max Sebastian Herring
Torres, for the first time in Europe his
European history, the criteria of race
and blood were used as a strategy of
marginaliz marginalization.
[clears throat]
A moralist like uh Torin Jasilio does
not hesitate to assert
that Judaism is is defined based on
blood regardless of whether conversion
to Christianity had occurred 21
generations earlier. So let me break
this down. What this is saying
during the Spanish Inquisition
>> they implemented something that was
basically a blood test. What they were
saying was, listen, if you're a Muslim
and if you're a Jew or if you're a Jew,
you can't convert. You are naturally
evil.
>> You are naturally evil. Bloodline. And
therefore, because of your race, you're
even if you converted to Christianity,
you didn't really convert.
And so they were persecuted and killed
regardless of their conversion, which
was a [snorts] forced conversion by this
by the Spanish.
>> So now now
>> I hear Yeah.
>> Wow.
>> So now here you have Wow. Within one of
these 10 horns, you now have this thing
of
What's your bloodline?
What's your genetics?
>> Your genetics determine whether you are
good or whether you're bad. Your
genetics determine whether not good.
Your genetics determine whether you're
morally upstanding or not.
And if you are not one of us,
then you are morally inferior.
This is what happens.
>> So we can enslave you. So we can enslave
you or kill you.
>> Or kill you because you're not really
>> That's right.
>> um
human.
>> That's right. And so
>> fully human.
>> Yeah.
>> And so let me go back to the screen.
Uh the earliest European initiator 1441
Portuguese explorers Nuno Tristeo and
Antonio Gonav. I don't know how to
pronounce that name either. all these
weird names. Sorry, not weird names. All
these different names. Sorry.
>> Conducted [clears throat] some of the
earliest known Atlantic voyages,
capturing Africans and bringing them to
Portugal in 1441.
By the 1460s, Portugal was taking
hundreds of Africans annually, and the
trade expanded as forts were built along
the western African coast. This set the
structural precedent for what became the
transatlantic slave trade. Europeans
capturing or purchasing Africans and
transporting them across the ocean for
labor. In that sense, Portugal is widely
considered the first European state to
systematically engage in what became the
transatlantic slave trade. Hold on.
>> Mercy. You mean one of the 10 horns
of Daniel 2 and Daniel 7
was responsible
for initiating the transatlantic slave
trade. This is what Christianity does.
And God is saying here, look, I'm
showing you these 10 horns because I
want you to see what corrupt
Christianity leads to.
How y'all doing so far?
Let me go back to the screen. Spain very
early in the colonial era relied on
enslaved Africans to provide labor in
the Caribbean and throughout its
American territories, often under
license or contract with from Portuguese
traders. In 1518, Emperor Charles I
issued a charter allowing Africans to be
transported directly from Africa to the
Americas, shaping the early scale of the
trade.
Christian theology was used to cover as
a cover
especially as interpreted by Iberian
political religious elites was used to
rationalize slavery. Conversion to
Christianity was sometimes used as a
rationale for enslavement or extended
servitude under the idea that submission
facilitated salvation.
Church orders, including the Jesuits and
others, often participated
in in [clears throat] or defended
slave-based economies,
Jesuit plantations in the Caribbean,
even while framing their involvement as
a path to evangelization.
Do y'all see this, you guys?
>> Some of the things that we think God is
silent on.
>> Could it be that the reason God said, "I
need y'all to track these 10." And we
just been tracking one. We just been
looking at one.
>> I know for the 30 or whatever years I've
been studying these prophecies, I'm
like, "Yeah, and the 10 horns." And you
know, you try to memorize them. You
know, the vandals, the the arch, and you
move on. You move on because you know
that that's not the real focus. The real
focus is the papacy,
>> right?
>> But when we begin to track these horns,
we're saying, "Wait a minute.
God is showing us the result of iron and
clay." That's what he's doing. He's
saying, "Listen, when iron and clay
combine, I'm going to show you 10
different ways
>> that what what happens when iron and
clay combine
>> which are counterfeits of the true mode
of evangelism, which is personal,
>> personal conversion,
not who's the right leader in whatever
office it is that is going to bring
conversion to the nation.
It isn't talk of nationalism.
Christ is looking at the individual.
I know you're speechless right now.
>> I am. It's very rare. [laughter] I mean,
I just have so many thoughts that
I mean, that slavery
was a part of this prophecy in Daniel.
That's like we've I we've never looked
at it like like we have never looked at
this prophecy and thought slavery was
there.
>> And God
prophesied of that, too.
>> 10 different manifestations
of what corrupt Christianity. And we're
we're we're on number seven right now.
>> Number eight. Number eight.
>> Number eight.
>> And it also just shows what happens to
your your way of thinking.
>> That's right.
>> Of what you can do.
>> What you think you have the right to do
>> the right to do. We have the right to do
this
>> because you had
>> in the name of Jesus.
Th those who participated and and and
did this, they had to have thought that
they had
the right or authority from God to do
what they were doing. And when you mix
together,
>> that's right.
>> Your thought process is is off.
>> Very off. I mean, that's just a very
nice way of saying it. That's very nice
the way I just said it. But
>> um it's insane, actually.
>> It's insane.
It's insane.
[sighs]
All right. So,
>> God doesn't want I'm sorry. God doesn't
want any He doesn't want humans to think
that they can take his place. And when
you mix church and state, they're taking
his place.
>> That's right. That's right. And And
>> he doesn't need a human government to
try to force someone to love him. That's
I mean, that's he's it's rude to him.
>> So,
>> it's like I can I can woo them myself. I
don't need you.
>> Yeah. So when the when the vandals
>> your ways are corrupt.
>> Yeah. When the vandals were persecuting
the Catholics because they weren't Aryan
>> Mhm.
>> in the name of God,
they genuinely believed that they were
doing the will of God.
>> When Clovis arms him, when Clovis
becomes the papal uh military,
>> he genuinely believed he was doing the
will of God,
>> right?
uh Spanish Inquisition,
>> we want unity. We want everyone to be
Catholic.
>> We genuinely believe we're doing you
cannot be converted because you're
you're a Jew. You're a Muslim and it's
impossible for you to be. When you
corrupt Christianity, it leads you to
think crazy and justify craziness. Mhm.
>> You guys look
>> people
>> look at what is going on today.
>> Yes.
>> And now you can streets in America.
>> In our streets in Now you can begin to
understand. Look at what's been going on
in our country. Now you But but I'm not
even jumping there yet. I'm I'm jumping
the gun right now. Let's go to hour
number nine.
>> Yeah.
>> All right. Hour number nine. Hour number
nine.
>> [clears throat]
>> Our number nine,
horn number nine is the Alamani,
which would be today's Germany.
>> Now, in the beginning, Germany is um uh
the Alamani are conquered by uh Clovis
um and they are absorbed into the
Frankish Catholic world. But then
there's an eventual separation and you
have modern day Germany, right? That is
not a part of a part of France.
>> Uh but they started off Catholic.
And I want to show you something here
which is very interesting.
Out of all the horns, out of all the
horns, this horn
is one of the only horns that becomes
Protestant.
So you got three horns that were
uprooted. You have all the other horns
that were Catholic, but the German horn
>> is the birthplace of the reformation.
>> Now that that becomes super significant,
you guys,
>> right? It's like, wait, what? Yeah.
Yeah. That's remember Martin Luther.
>> Yeah.
>> Yes.
It's almost as if within the T horns,
God is planting
planting seeds
that hopefully
would
stop the onslaught or stop the the the
>> the move of of the of the papacy. M
>> so here you have Germany which becomes
uh which becomes the birth place
birthplace of the reformation right
>> um
but check this out
after you know you've got the
reformation uh they're separating from
the Catholic Church but watch what
happens
there is something called the peace of
Augsburg
Um,
the piece of Augsburg, also called the
Augsburg settlement, was a treaty
between Charles Charles 5, Holy Roman
Emperor, and the I'm not going to
pronounce that either, League signed on
the 25th of September in 1555 in the
German city of Augsburg. It officially
ended the religious struggle between the
two groups and made the legal division
of Christianity permanent within the
Holy Roman Empire, allowing rulers to
choose either Lutheranism or Roman
Catholicism as the official confession
of their state. Oh boy, what just
happened here y'all?
What just happened here?
Can anyone tell me what just happened
here?
>> How can you have an official confession
of the state?
The Protestant Reformation, which which
birthplace is in Germany,
>> now begins to follow the same trend.
>> We're now, okay, you guys dictate that
you're Catholic and we have the right to
dictate to our people that we are
Protestant.
>> Watch this. The piece elaborated on the
principle
uh kulus regio eos religio
whose realm his religion okay whose
realm his religion if you're in this
realm you're that person's religion if
you're in that realm you're that
person's religion listen what it says
which allowed the princes of states
within the holy ro holy Roman Empire to
adopt either Lutheranism or Catholicism
within the domain domains they
controlled, ultimately reaffirming their
sovereignty over those domains.
Subjects, citizens or residents were
generally forced to convert to their
prince's religion, though a uh through a
principle called Louis or or called lus
reformandi.
Those who did not wish to conform to the
prince's choice were given a grace
period in which they were free to
immigrate to different regions in which
their desired religion had been
accepted. This principle is known as a
louisie immigr. However, surfs and
essentially or surfs were essentially
excluded from this right to immigrate.
So do y'all see this?
Even in the Protestant Reformation,
which by the way is one of the reasons
why
according to Revelation, Protestantism
becomes apostate.
>> Because they end up exercising the same
principles.
Are y'all following so far?
>> But there's another part of the Alamani.
I believe the the [snorts] re the the
the
actual part of the Alamani that we need
to understand y'all. Anybody think they
know what that is?
>> Hitler's Germany.
The Nazi worldview centered on racial
purity. The belief that the Aryan race,
lock that word in mind, y'all.
>> The Aryan race possessed superior
biological and moral qualities.
>> Mixing blood with Jews, Roma Slavs or
disabled persons weakened the nation.
The state had the right and duty to
repudiate to to regulate reproduction.
And Hitler himself said, "All great
cultures of the past perish only because
the original originally creative race
died out from blood poisoning."
You will remember that Hitler in a sense
partnered with the Protestant churches
and the Catholic churches
and use them
in his propaganda
against the Jews.
>> Whoa.
So you mean then
that one of the results of corrupting
Christianity is what we saw
in Hitler's Germany.
>> Wow.
Wow.
Wow. you guys
>> master race.
>> So corrupt Christianity then seems to
produce,
>> racism,
>> persecution,
>> are y'all following? M
>> y'all put a put a 10 in the chat. I want
to see how many tens we can get in the
chat so that I know that y'all are
following and tracking with what I'm
saying right now.
>> Could it be that what God is showing us
when he says, "Hey, I need to check out
these 10 kings. I needed to check out
these 10 horns
because
they're going to culminate in something
that looks nothing like Christianity.
If you thought Spain was bad,
>> wait until you see if you thought the
Franks were bad, wait until you see all
of these principles combined.
[clears throat]
in the tenth horn.
So, let's talk about this tenth horn.
Are y'all ready for this tenth horn?
>> I I should have Yeah. Are y'all ready
for this tenth horn?
>> Yes.
>> Okay. So, there is one horn left, you
guys. There is one horn left.
Uh, can anyone put that horn in the chat
for me? Do you think you know that horn?
Uh,
go ahead and put that last horn in the
in the chat for me.
And let's see. Let's see if you all can
can guess this horn.
I want to see it in the chat before I
put it up on the screen.
There's only one horn left.
And now we're talking about the 10th
hour. So the nine hours were the other
horns. All right. Here was their
manifestation. Here's Wow, look at what
Spain did. Wow, look at what uh Germany
did. Wow, look at what what what France
did. And by the way, remember that that
um France
ends up becoming atheist,
>> which is another way of God saying,
"Listen, here's what corrupt
Christianity leads to."
>> It ultimately leads to the rejection of
Christianity altogether.
>> Right?
>> Okay. So, yeah. So, someone tell me that
I'm looking for the old name of the
horn. I'm looking for the name, the old
name of the horn. So, some of you are
now saying saying England, but there's
another there's a name that I'm looking
for. It's two words.
Let me scroll up because maybe I maybe I
missed it. So,
>> let me just scroll up. Nope. Nope. Uh,
yes. Mucho
got it right. I don't think anyone else
got it. And probably the reason why no
one else got it is because we barely
remember the ten horns. Like who are
they? You had a test. For many of us,
the 10 saying the ten horns is like
saying the for other people is like
saying the ten commandments. What are
they again?
>> Right.
>> The anglo
>> Yeah.
10th horn. Everybody
>> mercy.
>> The Anglo Saxon horn.
The Anglosaxon horn.
That would be the horn that becomes the
British Empire,
becomes England.
>> So
um their conversion king is King
Athlbert
and this happens in 597
where they are originally converted as
uh as Catholics.
But there's something special about this
horn.
You see, it is this horn from which
White Cliffe
>> originates. Isn't that interesting?
>> Out of the two out of the 10 horns, two
of them become Protestant,
>> right?
>> The German horn, the Alamani and the
Anglo-Saxon horn,
>> Britain, when they became Protestant. So
>> I know what
>> Martin Luther
>> was
>> for
>> for Germany.
>> Germany and White Cliffe
>> for England.
>> England, right?
>> I'm I'm getting there. I see your
questions. I'm getting there.
>> Ellen White says this.
>> In the 14th century arose in England the
morning star of the Reformation.
>> John Whitecliffe was the herald of
reform not for England alone but for all
Christendom. The great protest against
Rome which it was permitted him to which
it was permitted him to utter was never
to be silenced. That protest opened the
struggle which was to result in the
emancipation of individuals of churches
and of nations.
>> John Wliffe morning star of the
reformation.
>> Henry VIII is the king who converted
England to Protestantism.
He initiated the English Reformation by
separating the Church of England from
the Roman Catholic Church in the 1530s,
leading to the establishment of the
Church of England and significant
religious reforms in the country. Are
y'all following this?
>> Y'all following this?
>> So,
that's why Catholics think they're the
or they call themselves like the mother
the mother church that everybody came
from them. Mhm.
>> So,
uh,
Germany and England,
>> the the two that that adopted
Protestant principles. Now, this kind of
is like, oh, wow. Wait a minute. So when
we're talking about like the little horn
and its ruling for the 1260 years and
how the Lumbards gave it its territory
and how you know uh the Franks gave it
its power and how the Suevi and the um
and the the uh Visagos uh um conquered
territory and and enslaved people on
their behalf. Uh and we're looking at
all these and we say, "Oh, wait a
minute. The German
>> horn
that started Protestantism, but then
they end up following the same path.
>> The British horn,
watch this. When their king becomes
Protestant, everybody becomes
Protestant.
>> Once again, you're like, "Wow, wow.
>> Look at this. Mhm.
>> Look, as soon as the king converts,
everybody's what the king is.
>> Yeah.
And so
we need to spend a little bit of time on
this Anglo-Saxon horn.
>> Yeah.
because you're going to see something
rise up in this Anglo-Saxon horn again
around the 15 and 1600s
>> around the time of the reformation that
you you're going to be like oh wait a
minute so so let's go to the screen in
in a book by Reginald Horseman called
Race and Manifest Destiny that's what
it's called race and manifest destiny
he writes this and I'm I'm going to be
reading quite a it here. So, so buckle
in, lock in everybody.
>> The first enthusiastical enthusiastic
English interest in Anglosaxon England
was a product of the English
Reformation.
As early as the 1530s, the Saxon Church
was studied to provide propaganda to
justify Henry VII's break with Rome. So,
let me pause for a second.
So it is at this time that England
starts really looking into this
>> uh this romanticized version of
Anglo-Saxon
history
>> where the Anglo-Saxons
were a purer people
as the the Romans, right? Rome was a
more debased people. and look at the
Catholic Church is evident,
>> right?
>> So, they start to let me go back to the
screen and and read a little bit more in
this same book, which I would suggest um
you know, you all get your hands on. The
main object of the research was to show
that the English church was returning to
the purer practices of the periods
before 1066.
supposed Anglo-Saxon precedents were
used to support the arguments the
argument that England had cleansed the
Roman Catholic Church of the abuses
introduced through centuries of paper
power. The interest in Anglo-Saxon
religious sources which helped to
justify the break with Rome also
eventually helped overturn the the
Arthurian
Arthuran legends which had dominated
medieval accounts of the origins of the
English people.
Whatever the eras of the rest of Europe
was or the rest of Europe, it was
believed that the English had clean had
cleansed had cleansed of corruption a
church whose roots stretched back
shortly to shortly after the time of
Christ.
The study of Anglo-Saxon institutions
provided justification for the English
rejection of papal authority.
Even German reformers drew an analogy
between the early Germanic or Gothic
destruction of the universal Roman
Empire and the new uh and the new
destruction of the universal Roman Roman
church. Theories were advanced which
foreshadowed the ultra tutinism of the
19th and 20th century. I'm going to read
one more read one more then we're gonna
talk about this for a second.
Um,
okay.
Throughout the 17th century, continental
arguments in praise of the Germanic
heritage were cited in English works on
the origins and institutions of the
Anglosaxons. Let me read one more.
In6005 vers dedicated his restitution of
decayed intelligence to James the first
ver uh versagen was a English uh author
and he wrote
a romanticized
study or book on the history of the
Anglo-Saxons and he says this descendant
of the chiefest blood chiefest blood
royal of all of our an of our ancient
English Saxon kings vers wrote with
passion on England's Germanic and
Anglo-Saxon past the German roots of the
English of the Germanic roots of the
English language and surprisingly for
this early date the common racial origin
of the Saxons Danes and Normans using
tactacitus
as his source he described the courage
and high principles of the Germanic
tribes and he emphasized that the
English like the Germans were an unmixed
race. The great invasion of England,
England by Danes and Normans merely
reunited old brethren. Germanic courage,
independence, and moral strength were
contrasted with Roman corruption and
decadence. So, let me show you what's
going on here. Let me tell you what's
going on here.
It is here that they are beginning to to
revisit
their their past and say, you know what,
our bloodline
>> was naturally purer than the Romans.
>> And this became part
of the the reason for their rejection of
the Roman Catholic Church.
>> They were rejecting people of other
races saying, you know,
the German blood. So when you hear, you
know, when you hear people today talking
about Aryan
>> and Anglo-Saxon,
>> this guys,
this is code word
>> for corrupt
Christianity.
>> So who is Tacitus?
Tacitus
was a um philosopher or a historian that
lived um in the first century AD.
Tastes said this, "In the peoples of
Germany, there has been given to the
world a race untainted by intermarriage
with other races, a peculiar people and
pure like no one but themselves."
This pure race, he argued, had a high
moral code and a profound love for
freedom and individual rights. That's
not like, you know, only a certain
people
>> have a love for freedom and liberty,
>> right?
>> And this is where it stems from. You
guys listen to this.
Roman historian Cornelius Ta Tacitus uh
wrote a book called Germania first
printed in Germany in 1473 in Nuremberg.
So his book in which he's lifting up
German blood
>> and talking about German his book is
released right at the time of the
Protestant Reformation
>> and the Germans in Germany are reading
this book and they are combining it with
their Protestant rejection of of
Catholicism. And they're using this
bloodline
plus rejection of Catholicism
that will be the basis for them
rejecting Catholicism.
>> Right.
>> Yes, Clint. This is all leading in the
same direction, y'all.
>> Revelation 13:11.
And I beheld another beast coming up out
the earth. He had two horns like a lamb
and he spake as a dragon. Let me pause
right here for a second. I'm going to
ask a question. This is a very simple
question.
>> But it's a question that many of you
have never probably never thought about
before.
>> What horn
founds the United States of America?
What horn?
Now you may have never thought before.
No, no horn founded the United States of
the 10 horns. The 10 horns, that's
Europe. The T horns, that's
>> Yeah. Yeah. That's before the paper.
That's, you know,
once the papacy, once a little horn
comes on the scene, we forget about the
T horns.
But you guys do realize that one of
these horns of the 10
is the founding horn of the United
States of America.
>> The tenth horn.
>> The Anglo
Saxon horn. Mhm.
>> You guys
>> Now, I hope I hope
I hope there's nobody watching right now
who's mad at me cuz I I'm not, you know,
not making stuff up.
This is actual history
>> and this is prophecy
showing us
what was to come.
>> We understand
that it is England
that is sending people here and pop and
and founding America. The founding
fathers, they're not from Spain.
Are y'all following me? Mhm.
So then
>> if it is the Anglo-Saxon horn
that ends up
founding and and populating America,
James Town and and and and
building
fulfilling Revelation 13 verse 11,
>> then wait a minute. Could it be that the
same Anglo-Saxon
racial purity racial Oh, wait a minute.
You know what? Wow. America and the
transatlantic slave trade. Oh my.
>> Is God trying to show us?
that the final iteration
of corrupt Christianity
will be seen in that beast in Revelation
13 11 which is founded by the tenth
horn. In other words, are we getting
ready, beloved, to enter into the 10th
hour?
>> That's the question.
And now a as we look back and we begin
to understand, you know what, there's a
reason why our pioneers identified
America as that beast in Revelation
13:11 primarily because of the
transatlantic slave trade.
>> Whoa.
They were actually pinpointing perhaps
without knowing it
that what happened in Spain and what
happened in Portugal and what happens in
Britain, all these things would
culminate. In other words, all nine
horns, all the things that happen in the
nine horns will culminate in the tenth
horn in the 10th hour.
Let me read to you. Let me read to you.
Um, go ahead, Dante. Go ahead.
>> Well, I mean, there's just so much. But
no, I mean, you're probably about to say
this, too, but what the 10th horn is
going to do and to try to I mean,
there's already on the books, but to mix
um church and state is just pulling from
all nine of the previous
>> Absolutely.
So when we see in Christianity today in
America the seeds of racism
>> when we see uh um the hatred of of the
inquisition
>> and yeah you deserve this because you're
not Christian when we see uh um the
>> trying to force people to be Christian
>> trying to force people
>> have a national day of worship
>> right when we see the fear of bloodlines
When we see the the concept that if you
are not one of us, if your bloodline is
not of ours, then you are polluting our
country and our nation.
>> All of these things are happening in the
in the nine horns.
>> Guys, God is good.
like he's trying to show us and there's
so many of us that are sleeping and not
seeing any of this and just like, "Yeah,
no, no, no. We're good."
>> When the Catholic Church starts to do
>> Yeah. When the Catholic Church does
their thing, then we'll be ready.
>> No.
>> Not realizing that.
>> And when we're unable to see the
corruption, that's the scariest thing
because it was the same for all the
other nine horns. They were unable to
see the cor. It made sense.
>> It made sense to persecute. It made
sense that that Germany that the Germans
were of greater bloodline that it made
sense. All these things made sense to
the people
>> when they looked to their leader as yes
that is the leader that God has put in
our country for this time and we will be
like him and what he believes we will
believe and we will defend. All of that
beloved.
>> Yeah. When you treat a president like a
king.
>> Yeah.
When Ellen White says that um the that
slavery will be revived,
>> she's not making stuff up.
>> All of the things that we are seeing in
the that we saw in the nine horns and
their history and you know what there is
so much more. Do you do you realize how
much like I didn't get a chance to study
how much I wanted to study and look into
this thing which I've been looking into
for the past like several weeks. There
is so much there. I mean going in into
these horns one by one and going into
the details of what else they did. It's
just stunning y'all.
>> So now I got to show you this. Okay,
we're almost there guys. We're almost
done. I feel like what we're living in
in America now is
>> definitely the spirit of those pre
previous horns and and really the spirit
has always been here but it's been um
well it's been in the forefront and then
it goes back into hiding and right now
it is Yep.
>> it's it's screaming the spirit is
screaming in the forefront.
>> We're going to get to Revelation chapter
17 you guys. We're gonna get there.
We're almost there. But I just need
y'all to see some stuff. Okay, so y'all
ready? Let's go back to the screen.
Let's go back to the screen.
I want to read to you from a book by by
Paul Kramer. It was written in 2003.
It's called The American Colonial State
in the Philippines, a global
perspective. And in this book, he says
this.
Yeah, that's not him, by the way. I'm
just going to go ahead and skip this
quote. Actually, let me go ahead and
read it. This is Uriah Smith talking
about the the horns of a lamb that
speaks as a dragon. He says, "Its
character, it has two horns like a lamb.
The lamb features a fit emblem of the
profession and the early acts of this
government, but it speaks like a dragon,
a fit emblem of the practice of this
hypocritical nation. Look at the
Declaration of Independence and the
Constitution. And then look at slavery.
Look at the religious intolerance, the
corruption and oppression existing
throughout the land. A further
development may be expected in the
future.
That was Uriah Smith writing about the
United States of America.
>> Wow.
Specifically, Protestant Protestantism
>> within America.
>> Our forefathers understood this.
>> They did.
>> Our our founding fathers understood
this. Prophetic founding fathers
understood this. All right, let me talk
about manifest destiny for a minute.
Manifest destiny is the term coined in
the 1840s to describe the belief that
the expansion of the United States
across the American continents were was
both justified and inevitable. The
phrase was first used by newspaper
editor John L. O. Sullivan in 1845 who
argued that it was America's manifest
destiny to overspread the the continent
uh allotted by providence for the
development of liberty and
self-government. This ideology was
rooted in the American exceptionalism
and the belief in the superiority of
American culture and institutions.
Okay, I'm going to keep reading.
Um,
okay. I think I may have lost some
slides here. I hope I didn't, but let's
see.
Okay.
So, in this book that I just mentioned a
little bit earlier, uh, um,
written in 2003,
here's what it says. Every race that has
been deeply
impressed that has which has deeply
impressed itself on the human family has
been the trans the representative of
some great ideas one or more which had
given direction to the nation's life and
formed to its civilization. Among the
Egyptians this seinal idea was life.
Among the Persians it was light. Among
the Hebrews it was purity. Among the
Greeks it was beauty. Among the Romans
it was law. The Anglo-Saxon is the
representative of two great ideas which
are closely related. One of them is that
of civil liberty. Nearly all of the
civil liberty in this world is enjoyed
by the Anglo-Saxons, the English, the
British colonists, and the people of the
United States. The noblest races have
always been lovers of liberty. That love
uh that love ran strong in early German
blood and has profoundly influenced the
institutions of all the branches of the
of the great German family. But it was
left for the Anglo-Saxon branch fully to
recognize that right of the individual
to himself and formally declare it as
the foundation stone of government.
So that's pretty crazy guys.
>> Let me keep reading. The other great
idea of which the Anglo-Saxon is the
exponent of is that of a pure spiritual
Christianity. It was no accident that
the great reformation of the 16th
century originated among Tutonic rather
than a Latin people. It was the fire of
liberty burning in the Saxon heart that
flamed up against the absolutism of the
pope. So do y'all see this?
>> Let me keep reading.
Let me keep reading.
It is not necessary to argue that the
two great needs of mankind that all men
have been lifted up in the light of the
highest Christian civilization are first
a pure spiritual Christianity and second
civil liberty. These are the forces
which have contributed most to the
elevation of the human race. It follows
then that the Anglo-Saxon
as the great representative of these two
ideas is divinely commissioned to be in
a peculiar sense his brother's keeper.
Yeah, y'all.
Let me keep reading. The author asserts
that the essential needs of the human of
humanity are a pure spiritual
Christianity and civil liberty which are
the foundation which are the fundamental
forces for societal progress. Therefore,
the Anglo-Saxon seen as the primary
representative and steward of these
vital principles is uniquely destined
for the world's future divinely
commissioned to act as as his brother's
keeper. Um, there can be no reason, no
reasonable doubt that North America is
to be the great home of the Anglo-Saxon.
By the way, the person that is writing
this, and I should have mentioned this a
little bit earlier,
>> the person that is writing this here,
>> his name is um, it's slipping my mind
right now. Josiah
Strong
>> uh lived in the 1800s
>> and he was a proponent of Anglo-Saxon
manifest destiny.
>> So he's speaking here
>> and the the the the link to what he says
to his book is a little bit uh is after
these quotes but
>> there can be no reasonable doubt
>> that North America is to be the great
home of the Anglo-Saxon, the principal
seat of his power and the center of his
life and influence. Not only does it
constitute seven uh seven 11s of his
possessions, but the empire is unsevered
while the remaining four 11s are
fragmentaryary and scattered over the
earth. Our continent has room and
resources and climate. It lies in a
pathway of the nations. It belongs to
the zone of power and already among
Anglo-Saxons do we do we lead in
population and wealth.
Mr. The Darwin is not only disposed to
see in the superior vigor of our people.
So now he's talking about Darwin,
>> right?
>> An illustration of his favorite theory
of natural selection, but even intimates
that the world's history and th uh thus
far has been simply preparatory for our
future and tribute to it. He says there
is apparently much truth in in the
belief that the wonderful progress of
the United States as well as the
character of the people are the result
of natural selection.
For the more energetic, restless and
courageous men from all parts of Europe
have immigrated during the last 10 or 12
generations to that great country and
have and have and have there succeeded
best. M
>> the text posits a future where
population pressure leads to a final
competition of races for which the
Anglo-Saxon is uniquely prepared driven
by inherent aggressive traits and backed
by number and wealth. This race seen as
the embodiment of liberty, Christianity
and civilization is predicted to spread
globally asserting its dominance over
Mexico, Central and South America, the
islands and Africa. The author concludes
by framing this exp this expansion of
the inevitable survival of the fittest.
So why am I reading why why am I sharing
this?
This is the idea of
um
the Anglo-Saxon
manifest destiny which says, "Hey,
America
is what it is
because
of who we are
>> as a race.
So the immigrants who are coming into
our country are messing with the
bloodline. M
>> they are crooks. They are criminals.
They are lower classes. And we need
to get the criminals
>> which are not of our race
>> out of the country.
>> Thomas Jefferson
>> among many others
are going to build on this idea of
Anglo-Saxon
heritage like It is it is baked
into the foundation of the church where
I mean foundation of our country
>> where you can see Jefferson and other
writers talking about our Anglo-Saxon
heritage and our Anglo-Saxon. And so
again, what am I saying?
And and when God is talking about these
horns, he's not talking about everybody
in the horns.
>> He's not talking about all French
people. He's not talking about all
Anglo-Saxons. He's not talking about all
Spanish people. But what he's talking
about,
>> Portuguese people.
>> That's right. What he's talking about
is when we nationalize our Christianity,
>> the result will always lead
to what we see in the T horns.
>> Yes.
So then there is coming a time and as we
look at what we're seeing now in our
country and so many of us are blinded
>> to this.
>> We think nothing wrong is going on. We
rejoice in what's going on. We're happy.
Yes. Yes. Yes. Go get them. We don't
even understand
>> how much we have been caught up
in the spirit of these ten horns
>> now.
Yeah. And I did lose some of my slides,
so they're not coming up, but let me let
me wrap this up with this.
So
in Revelation chapter 17,
we see these T horns
and
Ellen White makes a very significant
statement about the T horns.
>> Here's what she says about it.
I'm gonna see if I can quote it, but I
probably can't quote it verbatim. She
says, "Who are these powers that give
their power unto the beast?" And she's
referring to the t horns that give their
power to the beast, to the woman.
>> And then she says it is Protestantism.
She literally says the 10 horns is
Protestantism.
>> A power that while professing to have
the horns of a lamb speaks like a
dragon. Now, why does she say
Protestant? We just went through a whole
thing. Wow. Three of them were uprooted.
The other the other uh uh five were
Catholic and then two are Protestant.
>> Protestant
>> and then you have the little horn,
>> right?
>> Here's what's happening you guys.
It is this final horn
that will be responsible
for bringing all the other horns
together
when the deadly wound is healed.
All the all the horns which will be
symbolized by ten again will represent
>> Protestantism
>> which will then connect with that little
horn which is the papacy
>> which cannot be done until Satan himself
appears as Jesus
>> right
>> the whirlwind of Bible prophecy. Mhm.
>> So the t horns as they are they are uh
what's the word I'm looking for? They
are mutating as it were
>> right
>> throughout this time period of the fall
of Rome and and first there are these
nations but now they're turning into
something spiritual and now now they
become
now the the final iteration.
Watch this. Is an official United
Church state entity
>> that is the image of the beast on a
global scale.
>> But it's Protestantism.
>> It's Protestantism.
Catholicism is not gone. It's still the
little horn.
>> It's still there.
>> But the 10 become the completed picture
of Protestantism. The whole world. As we
said, when Jesus comes again, he's not
coming to destroy Europe. He's coming to
destroy the whole world. Meaning those
10 toes must come to represent the whole
world.
>> Right?
>> But within those other horns,
Catholicism
had its reign.
>> Had its reign
>> and it didn't do what this tenth horn
>> is going to do.
>> Is going to do.
>> You got it.
>> Wow.
Yeah, that's
>> Well,
>> yeah. And now you guys,
>> now as you look at the history of this
country
and you understand, whoa, this country
is really just the tenth horn,
>> right,
>> of Daniel chapter 2 or Daniel chapter 7,
and it's included in Daniel chapter 2.
We stop at Europe. We're just like, "Oh,
yeah, that's Europe." And then we move
on. We protect America. No, America is
not there.
>> America is not there.
>> Yes. God rose America up for a purpose.
>> Yes.
>> But in that purpose, just like just like
he did with Protestantism, but
Protestantism veered off. Just like he
did with Germany, Germany veered off.
England, England veered off.
>> America is going to be the final
and full picture. Let me say it this
way. The Protestants of America will
demonstrate what false Christianity when
it comes to its final to its most
um
completed state
>> what it will look like. And what would
it look like? It would look like the
Franks. It would look like the Suvi. It
would look like Portugal. It would look
like the Burgundians. It will look like
all of these other
>> uh kingdoms together in their
counterfeit representations of
Christianity all summed up
>> in one
with
the added element of Satan appearing as
Christ
>> to back up that counterfeit form of
Christianity.
>> Wow.
All right.
>> Well, that's the best study I've heard
on the tin horns that I've ever heard
just because I really understand it now.
>> Yeah. Um
>> because honestly, it just didn't make
sense to me. I was like, "Okay." And
again, God doesn't waste, but I was
>> allowing it to waste because I was just
like, "They don't matter. We don't have
to study those. It just It's just
history.
>> It's just Yeah,
>> it's not just history. I mean, it's
history, but it's there's it's in the
prophecy. Yeah. For a reason.
>> Yep. Yep.
>> All right. Well, what did we do? Two
hours.
>> You did really, really good. Like, I
didn't have to do any timekeeping or
anything. Look at that. Like, Yep. You
did two hours. A little bit over. Yeah.
>> But you did good.
>> Yeah. All right.
>> For you.
>> Well, thank you. [laughter]
>> Thank you. Thank you. Thank you.
>> Yeah. So guys, um I will uh I will
conclude with just really encouraging
us, encouraging everyone
to just please go get
get deeper into the word of God
>> so that as as you're looking and seeing
what's going on around you, you're just
not caught off guard,
>> right?
you're just not caught off guard.
>> Um
I I think it's I think it's just
unfortunate
how so many of us have gotten
on this train
>> of Christian nationalism whether we want
to admit it or not.
>> Yeah.
>> And we're just not seeing where this is
going and where it's coming from.
>> That's what I wanted shocking to That's
what I wanted to say earlier but because
I was listening so intently but um
you don't want to take the spirit of the
tenth horn and that's what's happening.
>> That's right.
>> That's what's happening right now.
>> That's what's happening. The spirit of
the tenth horn. It's it's a little bit
of vi and they don't realize it. Yeah.
It's a little bit of the Franks, right?
It's a little bit of all these spirits.
But this is just Satan priming the way
because when he appears
>> and Christians think they can partake of
That's right. the tenth horned spirit
because it's a Protestant
>> That's right.
>> horn, if you will.
>> It's all right for us to hate if you're
not on our side.
>> Right.
>> Right. It's all right for us to to to be
happy when we see
>> uh you know it and all of these all of
these spirits
the spirit of these 10 horns when Satan
appears
it's little now it is going to be
>> it is going to what you're saying
>> yeah it is going to manifest itself in
the hearts of all those who have been
caught up in the spirit of the ten horns
>> right
>> and it will be manifested
in all its power,
>> in all its darkness, and all its power.
>> Um, and that's what's that's the
unfortunate thing is people are
partaking of this spirit now and
defending the spirit and rejoicing in
this spirit.
>> And it's a scary thing to watch. and the
spirit of the, you know, ever since,
honestly, and this is honest, ever since
um Charlie Kirk was assassinated, I've
really been paying attention to what
some of these movements are doing
because honestly, I wasn't paying
attention to Turning Point USA
>> or the Heritage Foundation. I mean, I
was paying attention to Project 2025.
that was doing that. But when you look
at all of it, the spirit of all of these
horns,
>> yeah,
>> these organizations,
that's all they do. That's all they eat,
sleep, preach.
>> Yep.
>> That's their whole purpose.
>> Is to
>> um bring church and state together to
make their religious um beliefs be
>> enforced by the government.
>> That's it. That's all they do.
>> That's all it is.
>> It's That's all the T horns did.
>> It's the It's when you look at, you
know,
>> I mean, golden calf, I know, but I'm
going to do it anyway.
>> You know, the the almost worship of our
current president, Donald Trump, and oh,
he's a Christian and he's converted.
When you look at the Franks of Clovis, I
mean uh Clovis of the Franks, when you
look at Constantine,
>> you look at all these rulers, it's
almost like it is literally the same
thing. Like,
>> you know,
>> yes, our leader is this and I am this
too. Not saying that people were not
that before,
>> but it's the same spirit of who are our
leaders? Our leaders must be Christian
>> so that we can
>> evangelize this nation and make this
nation. The whole idea of making the
nation Christian again.
>> That is literally what the T horns
>> was all about.
>> Literally what the papacy, the little
horn, the 11th horn is all about. But we
are so locked in on that little horn.
>> We're not, you know, oh, the three horns
were uprooted. Some of us are just off
on a tangent. Those three horns are
uprooted because they're
anti-trinitarian. We need to be
anti-trinitarian. Missing the whole
picture,
>> just left side of the field.
>> So much that we I think
>> Yeah. Lord, make our hearts right
>> so that we could see.
>> I want to say this too, just like you
said, I don't remember which horn it
was. um that was saying, "Okay, we're
only we're converting because of
protection or or
>> for territory and power,
>> the Bragundians."
>> Um and
>> for protection,
>> right? For protection. But I just want
to say that
>> that
I'm sure was running through all of the
horns. Like it wasn't a true conversion
anyway. That's right.
>> Um so it's either you know what the
Bible says, the love of money is the
root of all evil. I know that that's at
the foundation of everything. And it's
no different
>> here here with the Tenth Horn in
America.
>> Yep.
>> Even with those um organizations that I
mentioned,
>> this isn't about like, oh, give your
heart to God and just love Jesus with
No, it's about power.
>> Yep.
>> Very scary.
>> Yeah.
>> But God doesn't give us a spirit of
fear.
>> That's right.
>> He does not do that. But he does um want
us to be wise and to study and to to to
know and to understand.
>> Yeah.
>> Um yeah. Well, we can say happy Sabbath
to everyone because there's definitely
the Sabbath everywhere.
>> Yeah.
>> And uh [laughter]
>> somebody said, "Think Greenland."
>> Yeah.
>> There's You guys listen, man. There
>> there's
>> listen there's so much going on that
sometimes in my like I'm just like
>> where do I even start?
>> You got to pay. It's like it's
everywhere and they want it to be
chaotic like that.
>> Yeah,
>> it was like that the first time but this
>> knowing that even to start you're going
to get some you know some Adventists who
are going to be like
you know you're and I'm just like you
know how how do you but you know what
those that have ears to hear will hear.
>> Yeah. And then those, you know, there
those that have itching ears that just
want to hear whatever it is that they
want to hear.
>> And this is,
>> you know, again, it's unfortunate, but
it it is what it is.
>> But I'm praying that none of you will
have itching ears. I'm praying that,
>> you know, those of you that are
listening will know.
>> Do not walk away from here. And it
doesn't matter. You know,
>> Pastor Myers is saying that all, you
know, all people of this race, that
race. No, y'all. No, no, no, no. This is
the Bible laying this out
>> and the Bible saying, "Listen, don't go
that route. Go this route."
>> That's all it's saying. Don't be a part
of this movement.
>> Right?
>> There's another movement in Revelation
12:17. Follow that movement.
>> We have another message which is to
convert people, not to convert nations.
>> Right? Don't worship a nation. Yeah.
>> I would go as far as to say
>> that this is not a Christian nation.
Yeah,
>> there are Christians
obviously here in the nation, but this
is not a Christian nation.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And let me say this guys,
one more thing real quick. So I see the
question. If all 10 horns equally are
equally corrupt, how can we then have
anything close to the trinity of the
paperal Rome? Let just I want you to
just you know just think this through
for a second. Um, all of the T horns
confess Jesus.
The Aryans believe in Jesus and the
Trinitarians believe in Jesus.
>> Because all of them believe in Jesus
doesn't mean that we say, "Well, we're
not going to believe in Jesus because
they're all bad and they they say they
believe in Jesus." Right?
>> We have to kind of think through these
things and not be like, "Oh, it's
association by guilt. if if they believe
this, how can we believe this as well?
Um, they believe the Bible is inspired.
That doesn't mean that we go, "No, the
they may not believe it's fully
inspired." We know that.
>> But they believe it's it's it's
inspired. We don't say, "Well, why
should we believe the Bible is inspired,
too?"
>> You know, they believe that there's a
heaven. We don't say, "Well, why should
we believe that there's a heaven, too?"
>> Um, because they, you know, they're
corrupt, and that's what they believe.
So, we don't we believe what the Bible
says. That is our basis for accepting or
rejecting anything. Not well, who
believes it.
>> It is what does the Bible say?
>> So, uh, with that said, guys, uh, we're
going to go ahead and wrap this up. I
pray that you guys, um,
learn something tonight. I pray that you
enjoy this message. By the way, I will
mention this. Um,
>> please share the message.
>> Yeah, share the message. Share the
message. Share the message. Share the
message. If this is your first time on
Power of the Lamb, which I'm sure it's
not, yeah,
>> you know, like and subscribe.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Make sure you like and subscribe.
>> And um uh if you want to support our
ministry, make sure you you connect with
us on Patreon.
>> And if you do that, uh I'll tell you
something at the next time that we're on
that, uh you will have access to if you
do that. But um anyway,
>> yes.
>> Make sure you like, make sure you
subscribe.
>> Yes. want to invite everyone to church
tomorrow. It's already the Sabbath, but
you can I was gonna say continue to
worship with us, but get a good night's
rest, wake up, and then continue to
worship with us. Tomorrow, Living Man
Church is at 12:00 p.m. Central Standard
Time. That's when we start our Sabbath
school. And then after that is the
divine worship service where Pastor
Myers will be preaching another uh
sermon.
>> And I'll be preaching on the house of
David.
>> The house of David. And you guys,
>> the house of David is not what you
think.
>> Never is what you think.
>> But it's it's, you know, by God's grace,
it's going to be it's going to be
powerful.
>> Yes. So, we would love to have you
worship with us tomorrow.
>> Yes, you can get the slides. So, I'll
make these slides available once the
video is fully uploaded. Uh the slides
will go out underneath it. And um may
God bless you. uh continue guys to study
this on your own because like I said, I
only touch the surface.
>> Okay? I only touch the surface.
>> And I'm sure like, you know, as as many
of you study, you're going to see things
you're going to be like, "Wait a minute,
Pastor probably didn't even see this."
>> So, there's there's a lot a lot more to
uncover in the dig. So, make sure y'all
do that. Okay.
>> That's right.
>> Um All right. Would you like to
>> I'll pray close in prayer
>> since I spoke the least. [laughter]
>> Heavenly Father, Lord, I just want to
thank you for answering our our prayer
uh for this evening, Lord. That uh your
Holy Spirit would be here to help us all
understand, Lord. And the study was very
powerful um and connected the dots very
well, Lord. And I just pray uh that uh
we will take this information, Lord, and
even study it some more and to go deeper
um on our own and that we will share it
uh with others as well. We pray that
everyone will get a good night's rest
and um wake up refreshed to just worship
you with others um tomorrow for Sabbath
in Jesus name. Amen.
>> Amen.
All right, everyone. God bless you and
um
see some of y'all tomorrow.
>> Yes, hopefully see all of you.
>> See all of you. [laughter]
>> All right, guys. Bye.